Tyler Anderson

Web Developer

Solution-driven professional excelling in highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing front-end consumer facing and internal web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, as well as back-end RESTful APIs to interface with existing databases. Experience building products for desktop, phone and mobile app users, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, usability and speed.

Personal Info

Address

Dothan, AL, 36305

Phone

(334) 714-6850

E-mail

jtacrimson@gmail.com

WWW

tyleranderson.io

Education

2014-08 - 2016-03

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Troy University - Dothan, AL

2010-08 - 2013-12

Associate of Arts: Advertising

The University of Alabama -Tuscaloosa, AL

Skills

.Net development

Javascript development

Data management

Testing and debugging

API design knowledge

RESTful API interfaces (JSON, XML)

Git proficiency

Languages

NodeJS/Angular

Javascript/Typescript

HTML/CSS

.NET

SQL

Work History

2017-03 -Current

Programmer

AngelTrax, Dothan, AL

- Maintained existing applications and designed and delivered new applications.
- Wrote highly maintainable, solid code in javascript/c# for the MotoTrax vehicle tracking system that formed core framework.
- Developed code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches.
- Modified existing databases to meet unique needs and goals determined during initial evaluation and planning process.
- Coordinated with hardware and system engineering leads to gather and develop system requirements.

2014-01 -2016-03

Technical Support Technician

AngelTrax, Dothan, AL

- Configured hardware, devices and software to set up work stations for employees.
- Documented all transactions and support interactions in system for future reference and addition to knowledge base.
- Engaged end users and answered questions via email, phone, website live chat and in forums.
- Explained technical information in clear terms to non-technical individuals to promote better understanding.
- Removed and replaced malfunctioning components to correct hardware problems.

2013-01 -2014-01

Computer Support Specialist

University Of Alabama E-Tech, Tuscaloosa, AL

- Configured hardware, devices and software to set up work stations for employees.
- Linked computers to network and peripheral equipment, including printers and scanners.
- Alleviated hardware and software issues affecting computers and language labs, resulting in improved relationships with training departments and schools.
- Setup, installed and configured computers in various business locations to support operations and reporting.

2013-01 -2014-01

Technical Support Specialist

University Of Alabama Academic Outreach, Tuscaloosa, AL

- Built website interfaces with HTML and CSS.
- Developed page layouts and navigation tools that met or exceeded user expectations.
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement.
- Kept abreast of emerging technologies, software and trends and project applications.